易考范文二十五
In the above drawing, a patient
who is seriously ill pleads with a doctor
for donation to have his disease cured,
but the doctor, who insists on the principle
that the donation must be earmarked by
its specified purpose only, refuses him.
It seems to me that the picture aims to
criticize the inflexibility in applying rules and regulations.
The flexibility does not exclusively exist
in distributing donation;
this phenomenon is rather wide-spread in the society.
Another case in point is that doctors
are not allowed to operate on patients
without the latter's family members' signature for approval.
It was reported that some patients died
when their relatives refused to sign and doctors,
mechanically conforming to the regulation,
did nothing but stand by,
though they were well aware of
the urgency of the situation.
As can be seen from the case,
rigidity might result in tragedies.
Similarly, great losses can be caused by
inflexible implementation of policies
without considering the characteristics of particular areas.
It is true that we are supposed to abide
by laws and regulations,
but under some special circumstances,
we should take humane or adaptable approaches,
which enable us to save more lives and avoid more loss.